Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
This is the main base of Captain M'Quve, who
controls Earth's greatest mineral resources.
This is M'Quve's main base.
The Earth Federation...
...is steadily preparing for Operation Odessa,
an attack on this base.
The White Base is continuing westward...
in order to join this operation.
However the assault from Ramba Ral's soldiers
is not over yet.
Sorrow and Hatred
One worn-out old Zaku...
...and four Magella Attack gun turrets?
Is that it?
It seems clear that Captain M'Quve
is not being cooperative.
I'm counting on you, Lt. Tachi.
I want to avenge Ral, no matter the cost.
We feel the same, Ms. Hamon.
Who is it?
Lt. Tachi.
The scouts have returned.
Enter.
Excuse me.
The Trojan Horse's back is to the mountains.
That gives us an opportunity to attack.
Yes.
What's the damage to the Trojan Horse?
They're working desperately on repairs,
but they have very few people.
Let's hurry. Continue the preparations.
Yes, Ms. Hamon.
It's pretty bad.
This ship won't last
if we keep taking hits like this.
And we're low on parts.
Ammo is running low as well.
We've got to plan resupplies at some point.
Don't complain, Hayato.
We can't predict what'll happen
on the frontlines.
We'll survive using our wits and ingenuity.
Our wits and ingenuity, huh?
Why not use Amuro?
Don't say that.
How are you?
Well, so and so...
Ryu, condition poor.
Ryu, condition poor. Ryu, condition poor!
Haro!
It's all right.
Ryu...
Haro sure is well made.
And honest.
Haro is well.
Ryu, get well soon.
Thank you, Haro.
He's even programmed to be flattering.
Is there anything you want me to do, Ryu?
No, not really.
Do me a favor and tell everyone
I'm getting along well.
Sure...
Tell me... Is it true that Bright
put Amuro back in solitary?
Yes.
Is Amuro really the one who's being stubborn?
I bet it's Bright.
The Magella Tops have been
rigged to the Cargo.
With the Gallop's spare engine,
it can travel at high speed.
We'll have the Zaku carry
a Magella Top's main gun.
We also have two Samsons.
There are 16 soldiers...
...all loyal men with long service
to Ramba Ral.
Thank you for the excellent preparations.
We came to Earth to avenge
the death of Lord Garma, but...
We have not yet completed the mission.
At first glance, this is a small operation...
...but the enemy is the Federation's
most advanced warship and mobile suits.
The people of Zeon have
great expectations of us.
Ramba Ral was...
...such an honorable man that
I may not have deserved him.
If it's to avenge the man who loved me so,
I won't regret dying in the desert.
Those who object to this operation
need not participate.
Ramba Ral won't hold it against you.
Neither will I.
There is no concern about that, Ms. Hamon.
Everyone is committed to the end.
Thank you.
I'm counting on you, Torgan.
Yes, Ms. Hamon.
You too, Misaki.
Illusin, I want you to do your best.
Yes, ma'am. I'll avenge him.
Bright.
Ryu...! Your wounds won't heal
if you're moving around.
It's my rehabilitation.
I should move my body a bit,
or it won't get better.
Are you all right?
Well... It's about Amuro.
I can't let him out.
If we act as though we're counting on him,
his head will swell even more.
That's not true. Right, Ms. Mirai?
Right. But there are rules...
Even a wild tiger will realize his position
if you leave him in a cage.
So, you're going to wait
until Amuro figures things out.
Sounds like you're making excuses to me.
I'm making excuses? How so?
Human beings can use words.
So while I'm still well enough...
Ryu, what are you saying?!
You've never really talked to Amuro,
have you, Bright?
The tiger will never be tamed then.
Call Sunmalo or Sayla.
Return Ryu to his bed.
Right.
If that boy gets in the way...
...my dear...
...please protect me.
All right. Now we just have to adjust
the magnetic pressure.
You're a pilot, and getting enough sleep
is an important part of your job.
Who's there?
W-Were you awake...?
Mr. Ryu?!
Sorry to wake you up.
Are you okay?
Don't worry about me.
Hey, I was wondering...
Now that Bright put you back in solitary...
...don't you resent him for it?
Me?
I understand Mr. Bright's decision.
I'm not angry.
That's all right, then.
You know, Bright...
He's afraid of you,
comparing you to a wild tiger.
Funny, isn't it?
A wild tiger...?
Amuro, I have hopes for you.
Are you all right?!
I'm fine.
Mr. Ryu!
Why are you up and about?!
Fraw Bow, this way!
He was over here at Amuro's.
Oh, Mr. Ryu!
Ms. Sayla!
Is Mr. Ryu going to be all right?!
He'll be fine.
Don't worry about him, Amuro.
It's a drill attack.
A tried and true method
of charging an enemy.
Our first strike hits what seems
to be the enemy's weakest point.
We focus on just one spot, ignoring all else.
Our survival will not be certain, but...
...we can surely destroy the Trojan Horse.
This is perfect. Damn Trojan Horse!
An enemy?
Oh no! They're behind us!
Enemy attack!
From where? Where's the enemy?
I won't let you!
They want to take down the White Base
with one Zaku?! That's some nerve!
Mr. Job John, can't you increase the speed?
It's not running well.
The damage from the direct hit
it received the other day hasn't been fixed.
Mr. Kai!
It's not just a Zaku?!
It's no use! The shaft is broken!
The engine's running, but...
Hayato! What do we do?!
What do we do?
We can't give much support from here!
Are you all right? Hang on, Ryu!
Never mind me!
Just get Amuro out of the brig!
I'll take responsibility!
I understand!
But you have to promise to stay in bed, Ryu!
I know, Ms. Sayla.
Bright...
Sayla! Where have you been?
Hurry to the bridge!
Give me the code to Amuro's cell.
What?!
Ryu's been here, talking to him.
He says he'll take responsibility,
so please send Amuro out!
That meddling...
I'll take responsibility too.
Please give me the code.
The code is F-36.
Ryu did this for you.
Do your best, for Ryu's sake as well.
All right! I'm going!
Damn Zeon! I'll get you!
There're more of them?!
Trojan Horse.
Just as we planned, you can't move freely.
I'll show you the tenacity
of the Ramba Ral team.
Mobile Suit
Gundam
Numbers 1, 2, and 3 show no increase
in power output!
It doesn't matter! Mirai! Let's take off!
Roger!
Sayla, will the Gundam be able to launch?
Yes, he should be ready to go!
Gundam, are you ready to launch?
The mechanics are all injured,
so repairs haven't...
As long as it moves, it's fine!
Amuro!
I'll have to launch in the Core Fighter!
Because of the repairs,
it's not docked with the Gundam.
I understand, Amuro.
White Base may be taking off soon.
All right, Amuro?
No problem!
Bright! Mirai! The Core Fighter is launching!
All right?
It'll happen even if I veto it. Right, Sayla?
Mr. Bright...!
We have no chance without the Gundam.
Are we gonna leave their graves behind?
Damn Zaku!
I'm not the same guy I was before!
I won't back down! I won't!
Can't you just lay down the bed
and launch the Gundam parts?! It's easy!
The procedure's in the manual,
but I've never done it!
That's how we do things on the White Base!
I'll figure out the rest!
All right! I'll give it a shot!
And he's the one who's supposed to be
a professional soldier...
Amuro! Here I go!
You won't mess with
the White Base anymore!
Fraw, go give them a hand.
Go to the starboard machine guns.
You can pull a trigger, right?
Yes!
Make sure you wear a helmet.
Or else you'll lose your hearing.
Right!
The Guntank's broken?!
Mirai! Can't we get the White Base moving?
We have no buoyancy!
The hyper-magnet is shot!
Launch the Gundam parts?!
Did Amuro say that?!
Damn...
Mr. Ryu! You mustn't get out of bed!
Your injuries are worse than all of ours!
Sickness and injury won't matter
if the White Base goes down in flames!
That's true, but...
Mr. Ryu! What are you going to do?!
Gotta get the Guntank moving.
If the White Base wasn't stuck...
...I wouldn't have been able to get out.
Just one so far, huh?
I should've come out earlier!
Amuro! We're ready to launch
the Gundam parts! You ready?!
Please do it!
The Core Fighter's out of ammo!
Launching Gundam B Parts!
Laser searcher, activated
Core Fighter, change!
Catch laser sensor!
Roll 180 degrees!
Attitude okay!
Looking good!
All right! Mr. Omur!
Launch A Parts as soon as you can!
Roger! Launch position, set!
Here it comes, Amuro!
All right! Good!
Damn!
I can hit the Zaku from here,
but the White Base will get damaged too.
Is hand-to-hand combat my only option?
Wait a minute...
Is that thing trying to ram us?!
That must mean it's packed with explosives!
No! Get back!
Trying to stop our charge?
How impudent!
The Gundam can't hold it by itself.
If it crashes into the Trojan Horse,
the explosives will...
Tachi! Get the Gundam from behind!
Yes, Ms. Hamon!
Another, from above...?! Can I do it?!
That Gundam took out two pilots at once!
I'd expect no less from the boy
who caught my notice. However...!
Oh no...!
Shall I shoot?!
You can't hit just the Magella Top!
However thick
the Gundam's armor may be...
...it won't hold up at this range.
The explosion from the Gundam and Cargo
will take out the Trojan Horse.
Ms. Hamon?!
I really liked you, dear boy.
This is the end!
Mr. Ryu...!
Ryu!
What?!
Hurry up!
The Core Fighter! Who was piloting it...?!
I get it! It's a hovercraft,
so if I just hit one engine...!
Take this!
There!
And now...!
Are there any enemies still around?
The battle is over, Amuro.
Are you and the Gundam all right?
We're fine!
Who was in that Core Fighter?!
Please stay calm, Amuro...
Y-Yes?
It was Ryu.
Ryu rammed the plane...
Mr. Ryu...?!
That can't be...
Mr. Ryu's injured.
There's no way he could go into combat.
Don't joke around, Ms. Sayla...
It was my fault... I practically killed him.
If only I didn't switch with him...
...Mr. Ryu wouldn't have...
He wouldn't have died!
Switch with me!
I have more experience than you!
But it won't work!
Idiot!
You have to think of ways
to adapt to the situation!
The Core Fighter can still be used!
Get out of my way, rookie!
I shouldn't have allowed
Mr. Ryu to launch.
Mr. Ryu! Are you going to be all right?!
We need all the fighting strength we can get!
I must have worried him
too much over Amuro.
That's not true. Right, Ms. Mirai?
He's starting to change a lot.
Never mind me!
Just get Amuro out of the brig!
I'll take responsibility.
Mr. Ryu...! Mr. Ryu...!
He's afraid of you,
comparing you to a wild tiger.
Funny, isn't it?
I was responsible for his death...
I was the one... I was...!
No! Stop that, Mr. Job John!
I feel that way too!
Maybe even Hayato!
It's... It's everyone! Everyone's fault!
It's as Amuro says!
It's because of our immaturity
that Ryu died.
And so many others were lost...
Forgive me, Ryu!
Please forgive me!
What are we supposed to do
from now on?!
Tell me, Ryu...!
Please tell me!
I guess you won't advise me anymore...
Mr. Bright...
Let's stop this...
All we can do is defeat Zeon.
And end the war.
That's right.
That's really it.
That's all we can do!
Bright collapses after Ryu's death.
As if to take advantage of that,
M'Quve launches a siege operation...
...quietly, and intensely.
A mid-air docking during battle...
...finally puts Amuro in extreme danger.
Mobile Suit Gundam.
Next episode...
The Trap of M'Quve.
Next Time
The Trap of M'Quve
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...